DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：因果律 モビイ·ディック 大湿 時間軸：水姬 後期：水姬 壓制：沙夏 KoU
嫌～ッ！
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
キャーッ
俺は降谷千紘
I'm Furuya Chihiro...
Shiyo Prefectural High School first-year.
県立紫陽高校の１年生
もったいない
What a waste.
I've long had a liking for zombies.
昔っからゾンビが好きだ
ビジュアルが
好きだってのもあるが
And while I do enjoy them on a visual level...
...ever since I was a child,
I've dreamed about getting into
子供の頃から夢見ているのが
ゾンビっ娘との萌えシチュエーションだ
romantic situations with a zombie girl.
や　やめて
N-No, don't...
Please shtop killing ush indishcriminately,
ゾンビだからって
無差別に殺すのは
jusht because we're zombies.
やめてください
Not a chance!
ありえねーって
お前
どんな趣味だよ
"Once I... Become a... Zombie"
What kind of sick tastes do you have?
どんなって　しょうがねえだろ
What kind? I can't help it, you know.
I just kind of think that would be cool.
何つーか　いいんだよ
そういうのが
何が　どういいんだよ
How do you figure that's cool?
Hmm, it's sort of soothing, I guess.
心安らぐっていうか
U-Uh, Furuya, probably has a soft spot
降谷君は　ああいう死んで
蘇ってくるような
for those poor folks who die,
and then come back to life. Right?
かわいそうな人に
同情してるんだよ　ねッ
お前　それ　絶対違うと思うぞ
I think you've got it completely wrong.
Huh? Oh, really...?
えッ　そう？
確かに違う
He's got it wrong, all right.
That's not what I would call it.
そういうんじゃない
"Hatano Tomato Juice"
Whatever the case, I just like them.
とにかく好きなんだ
Call it an impulse that not even I understand.
自分でも
よく分からない衝動っていうか
Shiryoji Temple...
紫両寺
うちは
そういう名前の由緒正しい寺だ
That's the name of the proper,
traditional temple where I live.
This is my grandpa, Jogoro...
これが　爺ちゃんの茹五郎
My old man, Do'on, the temple priest.
親父の呶恩　住職だ
妹の萌路　１２歳
My sister, Mero, age twelve.
My old man makes the breakfast,
朝食だけは親父が作るが
but she does all the other housework.
家事全般をやってくれている
いただきます
Thank you for this meal.
Mero, could you not put nappa in the miso soup?
萌路　味噌汁の具に白菜はやめんか
じーじ　それはキャベツだが
Gramps, that's cabbage.
えッ！　そうか
Oh, it is?
That's Babu.
ばーぶ
寺に迷い込んできた野良猫を
He's a stray cat that wandered into the temple,
俺が拾って家族になった
who I took in and made part of the family.
ばーぶ
萌路　味噌汁の具に白菜はやめんか
Mero,
could you not put nappa in the miso soup?
Gramps, that's cabbage.
じーじ　それは
キャベツだが
Aside from Gramps' mental state,
I think we have a happy family.
爺ちゃんがこんな具合である他は
幸せな家族だと思う
There's just one thing...
一つだけ
My mother passed away when I was little,
母親は
俺が小さい頃に亡くなった
and I barely remember her.
ほとんど記憶にはない
So, this is the makeup of my family.
だから　これが俺の家族の形だ
I'm content with that, and haven't
missed anyone. But one day,
それで満足してるし
寂しいと思ったこともない
けど　ある日　家族が
不意に一人　欠けてしまった
the family unexpectedly
lost one of its members.
Babu!
ばーぶ！
Ch-Chihiro, I...
He just jumped out in front of me.
千紘君　その…
突然　前に出てきたもんだから
間に合わなくて
I didn't have time to...
He was an old man from the neighborhood,
子供の頃から知っている
近所のおじさんだった
who I'd known since I was a child.
I didn't know what I should do.
俺は　どうしていいか分からず
All I could do was kneel there, shaken.
ただ　うろたえるしかなかった
Babu!!
ばーぶ！
"Babu"
I'm sorry. We can't hold
services for animals in the temple.
すまんな
寺では動物は供養してやれんのだ
We have parishioners who
are quite particular about that.
檀家さんの中にも
うるさい方がいる
We'll have to do with right here.
ここで勘弁してくれ
Brother...
Do temple children have to
stay strong, even at a time like this?
お寺の子供は　こういうときも
しっかりしていなければ
いかんのか？
No, of course not.
そんなことねえだろ
Okay.
そうか
I never knew that it hurt
so much to have someone
朝まで生きていたものが
寿命でもなく
死んでしまうってことが
who was alive just that morning
die from something other than old age.
こんなに悲しいとは
思わなかった
In fact, he shouldn't be dead.
It's not possible.
つーか　死んじゃダメだろ
ありえねえ
Then an idea entered my mind.
俺の頭に　ある考えが浮かんだ
Found it.
あった
去年　東北にある親戚のうちで
Last year, while at the home of a relative in Tohoku,
I found something while helping sort through
郷土資料館に
寄贈する資料の整理を
some materials to be donated to a local museum.
手伝った際に見つけたものだ
書物というよりメモ書きで
It was more of a collection
of notes than an actual book,
and I couldn't even
tell when it was written.
いつ書かれたものかも
分からない
The curator decided
that it was "of no value,"
学芸員は
価値なしと判断をしたんだけど
but I am almost certain
たぶん間違いない
that this writing dealt with reanimation.
これは
蘇生術について書かれたものだ
Maybe it was all nonsense,
but it was worth trying it out.
デタラメかもしれないが
試してみる価値はあるだろう
This was a place where the
neighborhood people didn't come.
地元の人間も
寄りつかない場所だ
ここなら誰にも邪魔されない
Nobody would disturb me here.
Indeed, I, who loved zombies,
そうだ　ゾンビを愛する俺なら
could love you, who are a zombie.
ゾンビのお前も愛してやれる
So come back to life, Babu.
だから生き返れ　ばーぶ
And so, on the second day...
そして　２日目
嫌～ッ！
ハハハ　アハ…
Brother...
何をしている？
What are you doing?
N-Nothing at all.
な　何でもねえよ
You can't be doing nothing.
何でもないということはなかろう
You can't fool your sister's eyes.
妹の目は
ごまかせぬぞ
I said I'm doing nothing,
and that's what I'm doing.
何でもねえったら
何でもねえんだよ
Suspicious...
怪しい
I'll be back soon.
行ってきます
なあ　聞いてんのかよ　降谷
Hey, are you listening to me, Furuya?
What? I'm listening.
何だよ　聞いてるぜ
Are you sure? That look
on your face says you're lying.
ホントかよ
その顔　絶対ウソついてんな
That's not true.
そんなことねえって
Then, what do you think?
じゃ　お前はどう思うんだよ
About what?
何が？
There, I knew you weren't listening.
聞いてねえじゃねえか
About our high school and the Sanka Girls'.
うちの高校と散華女子のことだよ
What about San-Girls'?
散女がどうしたって？
Sanka Girls' Academy, the foremost
girls' school in the prefecture...
県内有数の
お嬢様校である散華女子学園と
...and our boys' school,
with no distinction whatsoever.
何の特徴もない男子校の俺ら
Shiyo Train Station
So how come even our routes
to school are so clearly divided?!
だからって何で通学路までパッキリ
分かれてんだよ
Shiyo High School
Sanka Girls'
Academy
We go along the side of the river
to our schools. What's the problem?
川挟んで向かい同士
いいんじゃね？
よくねーよ！
That's the problem!
I specifically chose this high school
俺は近くに散女があるから
わざわざ　この高校　選んだのに
because San-Girls' is right nearby!
お嬢様方と
お近づきになれると思ったのによ
I thought I could get close
to some nice young ladies!
あッ　そう
Uh-huh.
特に今年は知ってるか
Especially this year. Did you hear?
超セレブな子が入学したんだぜ
There's a major celebrity that enrolled there.
ほらほら　あそこ
あの黒髪ロングの子生
There, you see her? Over there!
The girl with the long black hair!
散華女子の学園長の娘
She's the daughter of Sanka Girls' director,
Sanka Rea!
散華礼弥たんッ
なあ　いいよな
Yeah, isn't she great?
So neat and reserved.
清楚で　つつましくて
Sure enough, with parents that are outstanding,
やっぱ親が立派だと
娘もああいうふうに育つんだな
their daughter will grow up that way, too.
That's not necessarily true.
そうとは限らないぜ
What?! Don't be such a know-it-all!
何～ッ
お前　知ったふうなセリフを！
Hello!
こんにちは～
Ah, Ranko, thanks a lot.
やあ　蘭子ちゃん
ご苦労だったね
Mero said she would be late
today because of a school function.
萌路が学校の行事で
遅くなるっていうから
Just say the word any time, Uncle.
いつでも言ってください　おじさま
ごひいきさん置いて飛んで来ます
I'll leave my customers and come dashing over.
ハハッ　ありがとう
Thank you.
By the way, where's Chihiro?
ところで　千紘は？
Oh, probably lying down in his room.
ああ　部屋で寝てるんじゃないかな
Lying down?
寝てる？
He seems pretty worn
out ever since Babu died.
ばーぶが亡くなってから
疲れてるみたいでね
He plunks down as soon as he gets home.
帰ってきたらバッタリだ
He does?
そうですか
Chihiro!
千紘！
Oh, it's you, Wanko.
うん？　ああ　わんこ
That's Miss to you.
さん付けしろってば
Here.
はい
Huh? Oh, the DVD you borrowed.
ああ　貸してたっけ　ＤＶＤ
やっぱり忘れてたな
I knew you forgot about it.
You said you would come pick it
up over the weekend, right?
週末うちに取りにくるっつったでしょ
いや  ニャハハハ
I got busy with a few things.
色々と忙しくて
Busy my foot!
何が忙しいだ！
And that DVD was
pretty entertaining, you know!
つーか　結構
ＤＶＤ　面白かったじゃねえか
あッ　ところで　わんこ
By the way, Wanko...
That's Miss to you.
さん付けしろって
わんこさんさ
Miss Wanko...
何？
What?
Do you know the first-year, Sanka Rea?
１年の散華礼弥って知ってる？
Y-Yeah, I know her.
ああ　知ってるよ
What's she like?
どんな子？
どんな子って
She's the school director's daughter,
so I know her face, at least,
学園長の娘だから  顔ぐらいは知ってるけど
but that's all.
それだけだよ
What about her? Are you
getting the hots for her, you dog?
あの子が何だっての？
色気づいてきたのか　この～
No, no! It's not like that!
違う違う　そんなんじゃなくて
Yasutaka was making a big deal about her, so...
ヤスタカが気にしてたから　それで
Heh, here I thought you
were depressed about Babu dying,
ばーぶが死んでヘコんでるかと
思ったら
何とか　やってるみたいね
- but it looks like you're
getting along somehow, huh?
- I'm getting along! I'm getting along somehow!
- but it looks like you're
getting along somehow, huh?
やってる　何とかやってるよ！
Well, catch you later.
じゃ　またね
Yeah...
Make sure you come over this weekend.
今週末こそ　うち来いよ
お姉さんが　また
色々サービスしてやるから
Big Sister will take all
kinds of good care of you!
…たく
Sheesh...
And lend me another zombie DVD!
またゾンビＤＶＤ貸せよ
Just take one now!
だったら今　持ってけよ！
Sorry for the intrusion!
邪魔したな！
Saoji Ranko is my cousin.
左王子蘭子は俺のいとこ
Her family runs a
Kyoto-style "kaiseki" kitchen,
実家は京懐石の料理屋で
and she's a second-year at San-Girls'.
散女の２年だ
Her birthday is less
than six months ahead of mine,
誕生日は半年も離れてねえのに
yet she still plays the older sister.
姉さんぶりやがって
Sanka Rea, huh?
散華礼弥さんか
W-Whoa...
あッ　ヤベエ
Maybe I should have made a copy first.
コピーとった方がいいかもな
書物には１ヵ所
There was one part of the
book that was completely unreadable.
完全に読めないところがあった
"9. The noxious weed is added"
何かの毒草が必要らしいのだが
It calls for some kind of poisonous plant,
but I don't know what kind.
それが分からないのだ
前の日はドクゼリで試したが
うまくいかなかった
The day before, I tried
water hemlock, but that didn't work.
This might not work.
こりゃ無理かもな
I feel bad for Babu, keeping him like that.
ばーぶも　このままだと
かわいそうだし
今週いっぱいでダメなら 埋葬して
If this doesn't work before
the week is out, I'll bury him.
She's starting.
始まる
嫌～ッ！
Why was I born into the Sanka family?!
どうして私は
散華家に
生まれてきてしまったんですか～
私だって
I want to be able to freely
go out, just like everyone else.
みんなと一緒に
自由にお出かけしたいのに
なぜ散華家の娘は
Why is the Sanka's daughter
forbidden to go out alone?!
一人での外出は
禁止なんですか～！
- I'm in high school, already! Why? Why?!
もう高校生なのに…
お～お～
- Aww, she's been saving it up today, too.
- I'm in high school, already! Why? Why?!
今日も　ため込んでるな
それと
本当は　やめてほしいんです
Also, I really wish he would stop...
お父様
Father... would you stop...
あなたが
...taking naked pictures of
me every year on my birthday,
毎年　誕生日に成長記録として
to commemorate my growth!
私の裸を撮影するのを！
Now what?
困った
Uh... you're...
ああ　アンタって散女の…
...from San-Girls'...
I-I'll do anything!
So please, don't tell anyone...
な　何でもします
だから　今日のことは
...what happened today...
誰にも　言わないで　ください
Well, then...
じゃあさ
...what about what I saw yesterday?
昨日　見た分はいいの？
You mean you saw me yesterday, too?
昨日も見られていたのですか
Oh, should I not have mentioned that?
あッ　言わん方がよかった？
Oh, I want to die. I'd be better off dead.
ああ　もう死にたい
死んじゃった方がマシ
I want to die, and come back as someone else.
死んで
別の人間に生まれ変わりたい
まあ
何があったのか分からねえけど
Well, I don't know what happened,
アンタみたいな　いいとこ育ち
ってのも何かと大変なんだろうな
but I guess even trust-fund kids
like you have it tough growing up.
If I always had bearing and superficiality
forced on me by everyone around,
常に周囲から振る舞いとか
上っ面なこと押しつけられて
and had to go on living without
being able to say what I hated,
嫌なものも嫌と言えずってな
暮らしが続くとしたら
そりゃ時々　人けのないとこ行って
叫びたくもなるわな
I'd want to go someplace with
no one else around and scream, too.
By any chance,
ひょっとして
あなたも　ここへは叫びに？
did you come here to scream, too?
No, no, no, no...
Re-Reanimation?!
そ　蘇生術！？
Amazing. But isn't that...?
すごい　そんなことって
たぶん俺の予想だと
生き返るっつっても
Going by my expectations,
while he may come back to life,
he'll probably be like a zombie,
and just stagger around.
ゾンビみたいにフラフラ
さまようくらいじゃないかなって
Zombie?
ゾンビ…
If you ask me if that condition
is what Babu would want,
それが
ばーぶにとって幸せかっつうと
I'd probably say no.
そうじゃないかもしれねえけどさ
見てみたいんだ
But I want to see Babu up and around once again.
もう１回　ばーぶが動くところ
Well, long story short, I'm just
forcing my selfish wishes on Babu.
俺のワガママに　ばーぶを
付き合わせようとしてるだけだし
Frankly, I'm probably just
putting Babu out by doing this.
ハッキリ言って
ばーぶには迷惑なだけかな
そ　そんなことないですよ
N-No, that's not what you're doing!
I'm sure Babu wants to see you again, too!
ばーぶちゃんだって
あなたに会いたがってますよ
She sure is unguarded, huh?
無防備だなあ
Oh, come to think of it, what's your name?
そういえば　あなたのお名前は？
Huh? Furuya.
あッ　降谷
Furuya?
降谷…　さん
まあ　そもそもホントにその薬が作れるかどうか
You know, there's no guarantee
I can make this drug to begin with.
Well... Well, please,
allow me to help you next time.
じゃあ　次から
私にも　お手伝いさせてください
Huh? Hey, now, a proper lady like you
はあ？　アンタみたいなお嬢さんが
こんな　うさんくさいこと
getting mixed up in this shady undertaking...?
私の家って父が潔癖症だから  ペットは飼えなくて
My father is a big germophobe,
so I could never have a pet.
だから　私も一度くらい
So just once, I'd like to be
able to dote on an animal, too.
動物に愛情を注いでみたいなって
Oh, but if I'm going to be
in your way, that's another story.
ああ　でも
足手まといになりそうなら別に
No, it's fine.
いや　いいぜ
I do remember you saying before
that you would do anything, right?
確かさっき　アンタ
何でもするって言ったよな
Y-Yeah...
Well then...
それじゃあさ
ばーぶのために   この薬の実験台になってくれよ
...for Babu's sake, you can
be the test subject for this drug.
それって…
You mean...
You do want to die and
come back as someone else, right?
アンタ
死んで別人になりたいんだろ
だから  ゾンビに…
So... be a zombie...
Nah, I'm just kidding!
な～んて　ウッソー
Ha, ha, ha, what a pure-hearted
little snowflake you are!
クックック　さっすがピュアなお嬢
Just as I thought,
you'll believe anything you're told.
予想どおり何でもすぐ信じんのな
You have to watch yourself around boys.
アンタさ　男に用心しろよ
You'll fall for anything any
two-bit good-for-nothing will say.
つまんねえヤツに　すぐ
引っかかっちまいそうだからさ
H-How rude!
し　失礼ね！
I've... I've never, that is...
gone out with... a boy before, but...
私は  まだ
男性とお付き合いしたことは
その…　ないけど
きっと大丈夫ですッ
...I'm sure I'll be fine!
The bigger the princess,
the more pride she has.
お嬢だけあって
変にプライドが高いのな
W-Well then, Furuya... what about you?
じゃあ
降谷…　君は
どうなんですか？
Me?
俺？
D-Do you have a girlfriend?
彼女とか　いるんですか？
Nope.
いねえよ
Then you have no right to say
anything about me, do you?
だったら
私のこととやかく言える
資格なんかないじゃないですか
I don't have any interest in live girls.
俺　女は
ゾンビじゃないとダメなんだ
Huh?
俺  マジなんだわ　これが
For me, a girl has to be a zombie.
冗談だと思ってんだろ
You think I'm kidding, right?
I'm serious about this.
マジなんだわ　これが
Ever since I was a kid,
I've been like this.
ガキの頃から　そんなんでさ
I'd like to meet a living corpse
girl, but there just aren't any.
生ける屍の女の子と
出会いたいんだけど
なかなか　いねえんだよな
つーか　いなくて当然だって？
I mean, of course there aren't any. I get that.
そりゃ分かってんだけどさ
引いた？　でもホント
You buy that? Well, it's true.
Then...
じゃあ...
私がゾンビになったら
...once I do become a zombie,
責任とってくれるってことですね
that means you'll accept
responsibility, right?
それは…
Well, I...
じゃあ　それ
考えておいてくださいね
Okay, well, please think about that.
私　そろそろ
家に帰らなきゃいけないから
I have to get back home now, so...
Damn it, it feels like she
turned the tables on me there...
クッソー　何か
逆転された気分だ
あッ　そうだ'
And oh, yeah...
You'll be here tomorrow, too, right, Furuya?
明日もまた　ここにいますよね
降谷君
この時は   夢にも思わなかった
At that moment, I'd never have even dreamed...
...that she would ever...
彼女が本当に
Fu...ruya...
ふ　るや…　君…
ゾンビになってしまうなんて
...really become a zombie...
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
これ？
This? This is really what you want?
本当に　これでよいのか？
えッ　本当か？
Huh? Really?
これを書いた者と話はできぬか？
Can I have a word with whoever wrote this?
できない…
I can't?
では予告ですぞ
Okay, here's the preview.
Next time on Sankarea,
episode 2: "It Was... Successful"
"It Was... Successful"
みんな見るメロ！
Everybody watch mero!
お前　そんなキャラだったか？
Is that the kind of character you are?